William R. Ratchford Papers 1984.0021
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series II: Legislative Assistants, 1979 - 1984
  - Bob Godec
    - Connecticut
      - Disaster assistance
      - Community action agencies
    - Current action
      - Future floor material
      - Bergin/Statue of Liberty
      - Danbury reserve officer training
      - Response letter
      - Nursing home statement
      - POW/MIA - Carvalko/Dumas
      - POW/MIA - Donohue matters
      - Snokes, Dr., aging information request
      - Extension of remarks
    - Federal employees, (9 folders)
    - Foreign affairs, immigration
    - Health, (5 folders)
    - Health, (18 folders) (Box 19)
    - Health, (15 folders) (Box 20)
    - Post office, (3 folders)
    - ROBOS, (3 folders)
    - Social security, (12 folders)
    - Social security, (6 folders) (Box 21)
    - Veterns, (16 folders)
    - Vocational education, (14 folders)
    - Card file, 97th congress (Box 22)
    - Ratchford co-sponsorship notebooks (4)
    - Card files (Box 23-24)
  - Peter Slone
    - Academy selection (Box 25)
    - Active cases, (5 folders)
    - Age 60 pilot retirement age rule, (4 folders)
    - Appointment book, 1984
    - Biographical sketches
    - Budget, (4 folders)
    - Campaign 80, (4 folders)
    - Campaign 80, (9 folders) (Box 26)
    - Cities and towns, (22 folders)
    - Connecticut, (13 folders)
    - Economy, (8 folders)
    - Education, (15 folders) (Box 27)
    - Foreign affairs, (9 folders)
    - Handicapped regulations
    - Grants, (5 folders)
    - Health, (4 folders)
    - House Administration, (3 folders) (Box 29)
    - Nursing homes, (7 folders)
    - Resources, (2 folders)
    - Regional affairs, (11 folders)
    - Regional affairs, (8 folders)
    - Small Business
    - Social security, (8 folders)
    - Social security, (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - Standby economic recovery task force, (2 folders)
- Series III: Legislative Files, 1979 - 1984
  - General Legislative Files, 1979-1984
    - Abortion, (3 folders) (Box 31)
    - Aging, (14 folders)
    - Agriculture
    - Banking, (3 folders)
    - Civil rights, (2 folders)
    - Commerce, (6 folders)
    - Commerce, (18 folders) (Box 32)
    - Defense, (18 folders)
    - Economics, (9 folders)
    - Economics, (6 folders) (Box 33)
    - Education, (29 folders)
    - Energy, (28 folders) (Box 34)
    - Environment, (12 folders)
    - Environment, (15 folders) (Box 35)
    - Ethics, (4 folders)
    - Foreign relations, (2 folders)
    - Government operations
    - Health, (2 folders)
    - Housing, (4 folders)
    - Housing, (9 folders) (Box 36)
    - Human rights, (6 folders)
    - Immigration, (2 folders)
    - Judiciary, (9 folders)
    - Labor, (13 folders)
    - Labor, (20 folders) (Box 37)
    - Social problems, (5 folders) (Box 38)
    - Taxation, (12 folders)
    - Trade policies, (6 folders)
    - Trade policies, (3 folders) (Box 39)
    - Transportation, (13 folders)
    - Urban affairs, (2 folders)
    - Veterns, (2 folders)
    - Welfare, (3 folders)
  - Floor Files, 1979 - 1984 (Box 40-49)
    - 1979 February - 1984 October
    - Subject files (Box 50-51)
  - Record Vote (Box 52)
    - Bills introduced, 1983-1984
    - Sponsored measures, 1983 January - 1984 November
    - Co-sponsored measures, 1983 January - 1984 September; (3 folders)
    - Sponsored measures organized by committee referal, 1983 February - July
    - Superceded measures, 1983 June - 1984 October
    - Sponsored amendments, 1984 June - August
- Series IV: Press Secretaries, 1979 - 1985
  - Kevin Lynch, 1981-1985
    - Aging - adult day care legislation (Box 53)
    - Budget, 1984-1985; (2 folders)
    - Business, small business task force
    - Campaigns, 1980-1982; (2 folders)
    - Commodore Hull Bridge
    - Editorials, (2 folders)
    - Education, (2 folders)
    - Environmental waste removal, Waterbury, (2 folders)
    - Equal rights movement, 1982
    - Foreign affairs - Poland
    - Franking commission
    - Grants, (2 folders)
    - HR 5969
    - HR 6320
    - HR 6985
    - Interns
    - Industry, district expansion cutbacks
    - Ku Klux Klan
    - Legislation, (3 folders)
    - Letters to the Editor
    - Minority affairs
    - New members orientation
    - Newsletter, (3 folders)
    - 97th congress
    - 98th congress
    - Office hours
    - Pay raise, lame duck session, 1982
    - Press, 1984 September - October
    - Radio feeds, scripts and logs
    - Railroads
    - Ratchford, (3 folders)
    - Reagan, (2 folders)
    - Recording studio
    - Redistricting
    - Religious groups, churches
    - Reprints
    - Service academy nominations, 1983
    - Social security forums, 1981; (2 folders)
    - Statements
    - Steering and policy committee
    - Town meetings
    - Transportation, transit panel, etc.
    - TV, (4 folders)
    - NCPAC hit list reaction
    - Unemployment, 1982
    - Vietnam veterans, (2 folders)
  - Jason Isaacson, 1980 - 1982
    - Air traffic controllers (Box 54)
    - Arts - congressional arts caucus
    - Atlanta killings
    - Bizarre door material
    - Block grants and reaction
    - Budget, 1980-1981; (2 folders)
    - Coastal management bill
    - Congressional town meeting
    - Connecticut flood
    - Correspondence to Ratchford
    - Countercyclical aid
    - Crime
    - Defense issues - nerve gas
    - Draft registration
    - DSG fact sheets and special reports
    - Economic Development Administration
    - Economy, nation wide
    - Election campaign
    - Energy, (8 folders)
    - Environment, (4 folders)
    - Export conference
    - Flood valley crisis
    - Food stamps
    - Foreign relations, (6 folders)
    - Foreign aid
    - Handicapped education
    - HUD
    - Inflation/Carter, 1980
    - Israel
    - Italian immigration/quake
    - Job information resume
    - Labor
    - Legislative service organizaiton
    - Lifelong learning
    - Mail, (2 folders)
    - Notes to press
    - Mobile office schedule
    - Newsclippings, (35 folders)
    - Newsletter, (2 folders) (Box 55)
    - Open space grants
    - Parental kidnapping
    - Pay raises - other perk issues
    - Postal fraud
    - Press relations
    - Procurement, (3 folders)
    - Promotional spots
    - Publications
    - Public works
    - Race relations
    - Radio feed forms
    - Ratchford, (4 folders)
    - Revenue sharing
    - School lunches
    - Service academy acceptances
    - Sodium vapor lights
    - Soviet Union
    - Special report
    - Statements issues floor remarks, (3 folders)
    - Statistical data
    - Tax bill, 1982
    - Tax policy
    - Transportation - Waterbury & Bridgeport
    - Voting records - special interest tabs, attendance
    - Whip issue paper
    - White House releases
    - WMNR
    - Wild Bill Ratchford's Christmas songbook, 1980
    - Women, (2 folders)
    - Workfare
  - Jason Isaacson, 1979 - 1980
    - Airline pilots (Box 56)
    - Aging, (4 folders)
    - Agriculture
    - Arson
    - Bill Ratchford
    - Blank sheets for NMC campaign
    - Boarding home legislation
    - Budget, press
    - Cable TV
    - Campaign releases
    - Census
    - Clipping reproductions
    - Column
    - Committees, (2 folders)
    - Correspondence
    - Credit Union
    - Criminal code/crime
    - Defense
    - District staff, (2 folders)
    - DMSO
    - DNMC cammmpaigning
    - Draft
    - Education and Labor, (6 folders)
    - Electoral college
    - Employment, (2 folders)
    - Energy, (14 folders)
    - Environment, (2 folders)
    - Ethics, (2 folders)
    - Federal government and bureau, (3 folders)
    - 5th district - public leaders, (4 folders)
    - Flood
    - Food stamps
    - Freeman v. Mitchell
    - Grants, (2 folders)
    - Guidera, George
    - Gun control
    - Handbook to student financial aid
    - Health
      - Lower Naugatuck Valley Mental Health
      - National health insurance
    - Hold
    - HVCEO
    - Incoming letters - Hull
    - Independent local newspaper act
    - Inflation, (2 folders)
    - Issues, (2 folders)
    - Judiciary
    - Labor
    - Leg hold traps
    - Legislative agenda, (2 folders)
    - Media, (3 folders)
    - Memo to editors
    - Mental health
    - Middle East
    - Minority
    - Miscellaneous
    - Newsletters
    - Newspaper subscriptions, DC
    - News releases
    - OEO - Redding case
    - Office
    - Pay raise
    - Politics, (5 folders) (Box 57)
    - Poll results
    - Pork barrel legislation (Waterworks)
    - PR higher education conference
    - Presidential race
    - Press releases
    - Procurement, (2 folders)
    - QWIP
    - Radio feed files, (2 folders)
    - Railroad/railroad act
    - Ratchford on the Issues, newsletter, 1980
    - Ratchford report
    - Republican National Committee releases
    - Revenue sharing, (2 folders)
    - Roll call
    - Route 7
    - Russian watches
    - Senate race
    - Small business
    - Soviet Jewry
    - Social security
    - State of the Union
    - Summer radio feeds
    - Taxes, (3 folders)
    - Television, house use of
    - Thomas affair
    - Town co-ordinators, biographies
    - Transportation, (2 folders)
    - Tri state
    - Van, (2 folders)
    - Veterans affairs
    - Welfare
    - Western Connecticut
    - Windfall oil profits
    - WMNR
    - WNBC
    - Youth camp
    - Youth
  - Steve Singer
    - Press Files (Box 58)
      - Acid Rain
      - AHDPA
      - Applachian Trail
      - Arts funding
      - Art competition
      - Assorted letters
      - AVCO
      - Broadcast
        - AM daytime bill
        - Deregulation
        - Financial and syndication
        - Radio marti [sic]
      - Budget
        - 1984
        - 1985
      - Business cases
      - Cable TV
      - Cheshire
      - Children and nuclear war
      - Chimon Island
      - Communications
        - Home recording
        - Religious broadcasters
        - Telephone regulations
      - ConnectiCOSH
      - Congressional Research Service
      - Contract awards
      - Convention
      - Coal leasing
      - Danbury IRS
      - December issue summary
      - Deficit
      - Democratic campaign committee
      - Democratic media center
      - Disability - social security
      - Distribution mail breakdowns
      - Easton
      - Education, (2 folders)
      - Economic program
      - Endorsements
      - Election reform
      - El Salvador
      - EPA
      - Euromissiles
      - Event
        - Consumer fair
        - Mo Udall
        - Tip O'Neill
      - Fair tax
      - Flat tax
      - Federal employees
      - Federal funds - Connecticut
      - Ferraro, Geraldine
      - Financial disclosure
        - 1982
        - 1983
      - Flood assistance
      - Foreign affairs
        - Lebanon
        - Central America
      - Franking commission
      - Freeze
      - Georges bank
      - Girl Scouts awards
      - Grenada
      - Grant announcements
      - Groundwater pollution
      - Health care
        - Costs
        - Unemployed
      - Hospices, (2 folders)
      - Housatonic River
      - House, Art
      - House recording studio
      - Human services
      - IMF
      - Interior, Dept. of, (2 folders)
      - Korean airliner tragedy
      - Jobs bill, 1984
      - Ku Klux Klan
      - Latin American policy
      - Laurel park landfill
      - Leadership speeches
      - Lebanon
      - Legislative update
      - Letters
      - Library
      - Luca, Joseph
      - Medical quackery
      - Medicare
      - Memo (Box 59)
      - Mianus River bridge
      - Miller, 1984
      - Miscellaneous appearances
      - Miscellaneous statements
      - MX missile
      - National Public Radio
      - National Register Historic Places
      - Natural gas
      - NCAT
      - NCPAC
      - Nerve gas
      - Nuclear freeze
      - Nursing homes
      - OSHA
      - Originals - basic releases
      - Personnel matters
      - Phantom taxes
      - Photographers
      - Polls
      - Potential opponents GOP
      - Pratt & Whitney
      - Printer
      - Procurement
      - Publications
      - Questionnaires
      - Ratchford
        - Announcement
        - Biography
        - LLIPS
        - Voting record
        - Views
        - Consumer
        - Freeze
      - Reagan Speeches
      - Road repair newsletter
      - Rowland, John
      - Schlessinger, Alan R. - Derby
      - Shelton
        - Hull bridges
        - Landfill
      - Tariff adjustments
      - Tandem trucks
      - Task force on social security and women
      - Team
      - Telecommunications
      - Telephone deregulation
      - 10% withholding
      - Unsolicited letters - favorable
      - TV - Ratchford report
      - Veterns administration
      - Veterans
        - Art show
        - Agent Orange
        - Vietnam
      - Vietnamese orphans crash victims
      - Vocational education
      - Watt, James
      - Whales
      - Women's issues
    - Press Releases (Box 60)
    - Issue Updates & Newsletters (Box 61)
      - Office hours, 1983
      - Town meetings, 1983
      - Special forums, 1983
      - Posters, 1983
      - Newsletters, 1983
      - Financial aid book, 1983
      - Consumer guides, 1983
      - Procurement mailing, 1983
      - Newsletters, 1984
      - Issue Update, 1984 January
      - Student financial aid, 1984
      - Older American guide, 1984
      - Veterns guide, 1984
      - Welcome to Washington, 1984
    - Ratchford Column
      - FY 85 Appropriations, undated
      - Cleaning up the EPA, 1983 March 25
      - 5th district residents share, 1983 April 1
      - Holocaust victims remember, 1983 April 15
      - Tracking the Metro-North, 1983 April 22
      - Politics and driving don't always mix, 1983 April 29
      - Medicare: we have the time to do it right, 1983 May 6
      - Watt's wrong with the Department of the Interior, 1983 May 13
      - Remember America's veterans, 1983 May 20
      - The MX: the turkey that continues to fly, 1983 May 27
      - Affirming our commitment to civil rights, 1983 June 3
      - Congress recognizes women need jobs too, 1983 June 10
      - Tandem truck ban, 1983 June 17
      - Restrain Interior Department, 1983 June 24 (Box 62)
      - Medal of honor, 1983 July 1
      - Education, 1983 July 15
      - Mianus bridge, 1983 July 22
      - Peace to Central America, 1983 July 29
      - 98th Congress summer break, 1983 August 5
      - Foreign policy dominates 98th Congress, 1983 August 16
      - Social security, 1983 August 26
      - James Watt, 1983 September 30
      - New federal job programs, 1983 October 7
      - Student aid, 1983 October 14
      - Pershing missile, 1983 October 21
      - UN forces in Lebanon, 1983 November 4
      - Technological revolution, 1983 November 11
      - Case for equality, 1983 November 18
      - Acid rain legislation, 1983 November 25
      - 1983: a good year for Congress, 1983 December 1
      - Hospice: terminally ill patients, 1983 December 9
      - Congressional recess, 1983 December 16
      - 98th Congress ready for session, 1984 January 13
      - Medicare, 1984 January 20
      - Government security, 1984 January 27
      - 1985 budget, 1984 February 3
      - Repairing roads and bridges, 1984 February 10
      - Older Americans, 1984 February 24
      - Avoiding another oil crisis, 1984 March 12
      - Consitutent service, 1984 March 16
      - Tandem rules, 1984 March 23
      - Income taxes, 1984 March 30
      - Federal budget, 1984 April 6
      - Educators debate: children's fear of nuclear war, 1984 April 13
      - Foreign affairs, 20 Apr 1984
      - World War II: day of rememberance, 1984 April 27
      - Regionalism and acid rain, 1984 May 11
      - Memorial Day, 1984 May 18
      - El Salvador, 1984 May 25
      - Medical quackery, 1984 June 1
      - Ridgefield students, 1984 June 8
      - Appropriations Committee, 1984 June 22
      - Deficit, 1984 June 29
      - Appropriations, 1984 July 27
      - Oil, 1984 August 3
      - Tandem: bi-partisan support, 1984 August 10
      - End of Congress summer vacation Photographs of Ratchford with interns, 1984 September 7
      - Photographs of Ratchford
        - in groups
        - portraits
        - with other members (Box 63)
        - Appropriations committee
        - Interior subcommittee
        - Transportation subcommittee
        - Aging committee
        - other government officials
        - Sikorsky plant tour
- Series V: Press Files, 1979 - 1983
  - Postal Patron Mail (Box 64)
    - Area office hours, 1981-1982; (2 folders)
    - Town meetings, 1981-1982; (2 folders)
    - Procurement brochure, 1982 Spring
    - Consumer book, 1982 Spring
    - Newsletter, 1982 Spring
    - Issue update, 1982
    - Aging/IRS newsletter, 1981
    - Newsletter, 1981 March
    - Energy fair issue update, 1981 February
    - Social security fact sheet, 1981
    - Consumer information catalog, 1981
    - Special report, 1981 August
    - Energy fair, 1981 Fall
    - Guide for older Americans, 1980
    - Vietnam vets forum, 1981
    - Foreign affairs forum, 1982
    - Issue report, 1981
    - Brookfield/Sandy Hook letters, 1981
    - Posters and certificates, 1981
    - Newsletter, 1981 November
    - Tour book, 1981-1982
  - William Ratchford Column
    - 1980 March 21 - 1983 March 18 (Box 65)
  - Press Releases and Statements (Box 66)
    - Press Releases
      - 1979 January 19 - 1983 March 16
    - Newspaper articles
    - Western forum
    - Fair press
  - Issue Briefs (Box 67)
    - Issue briefs, 1979 July 5
    - Consumer bulletin, 1979 Fall
    - Academy poster, 1979
    - Aging handbook, 1980 January
    - College aid guide, 1980 January
    - Newsletter follow-up, 1980 January
  - Town Meeting Notices, (34 folders) (Box 68)
- Series VI: Committee Files, 1979 - 1985
  - Select Aging Committee, 1979 - 1983 (Box 69)
    - Age discrimination Act
    - Draft of 1980 Aging handbook
    - Reduced Amtrack fares for the elderly
    - Hearings on boarding houses, (2 folders)
    - Cancer, (3 folders)
    - Channelling agency demonstration hearing
    - Co-sponsorship, proposed
    - Crime, fraud, and abuse, (4 folders)
    - Demonstration and unique projects
    - EEOC's enforcement of ADEA
    - Employee retirement income security act - ERISA
    - ERISA H.R. 3904, revised, (2 folders)
    - Families
    - FY 80 budget, impact on the elderly
    - FY 81 first budget resolution
    - General (Box 70)
    - Home health care, (2 folders)
    - Housing
    - Hypothermia hearing
    - Interagency agreements hearing
    - Judges age discrimination hearing
    - Keyes amendments, (2 folders)
    - Legal, (2 folders)
    - Life long learning, general information
    - Long term care options
    - Medigap insurance policies
    - Mental health conference
    - Minority elderly hearings
    - National conference on statewide education, occupation information, and counseling
    - Nursing homes, (3 folders)
    - Nutrition programs
    - Older American act, (5 folders)
    - Older American act, (3 folders) (Box 71)
    - Payroll taxes
    - Pensions hearings
    - Pilot aging testimony
    - Representative payees, problems with
    - Retirement
    - RSVP
    - Select committee on aging
    - Senior citizen interns
    - Senior environment employment programs
    - Senior tutor for educational progress
    - Social services
    - Social security, (2 folders)
    - Space application for elderly
    - State of the elderly in America hearing
    - Title I
    - Unemployment and aging hearing
    - Women, problems of midlife
    - White House conference on aging, (2 folders)
  - Health and Long-Term Care Subcommittee (Box 72)
    - Carter health program
    - Chrysler program
    - Developmental disability
    - Emergency health services
    - Hospital cost containment, (2 folders)
    - HSA
    - National health insurance
  - Education and Labor Committee, 1979 - 1982 (Box 73)
    - Army corps
    - Asbestos in schools: H.R. 1524, (2 folders)
    - Brown dust
    - Cargo preference
    - CETA
    - Child nutrition hearing, 1981 March 10
    - Chrazanowski, David
    - Civilian marksmanship program
    - Clearing house
    - Clearing house for community bases educational institutions
    - Collection agency legislation
    - Consumer protection agency
    - Defence budget
    - Domestic violence act
    - Donovan testimony, 1982 budget cuts
    - Education
    - Education/labor
      - Budget for FY, 1980
      - Committee reconciliation
      - Hearing, reconciliation, Secretary Bell, 1981 March 20
      - Hearing on H.R. 3818 diffusion
      - Hearing on H.R. 66 student organizations
      - Hearing on robotics
      - H.R. 2977 and H.R. 2196 markups, 1979 September 26
      - Child abuse, alcohol and drugs, markups
      - Reconciliation
      - Reconciliation cuts FY, 1982
      - Recommendations on FY 1982 budget
    - Education work council
    - Elementary guidance and counseling act, hearing, 1981 April 9
    - Equal employment opportunity
    - FTC - funeral service rules
    - General background, education
    - Hearings: (Box 74)
      - Library programs, 1981 April 7
      - CETA shortfall, committee oversight, 1979 March 7
      - Youth employment programs, 1979 June 20
      - Employment trends for women, 1981 July 9
      - H.R. 3583 Energy/manpower, 1979 May 16
      - H.R. 4465 Youth employment Hawkins, 1979 June 29
      - H.R. 27 Child nutrition act
      - H.R. 2222 and H.R. 4774, 1979 September 19
      - H.R. 3292 Action resolution
      - H.R. 4136 Child nutrition act
      - H.R. 5540 Defense industry revitalization act (Box 75)
      - H.R. 6250 Community renewel employment act
      - H.R. 6615 NIE Extension
      - H.R. 6619 Weatherization economic opportunity
      - H.R. 6711 Youth act
      - H.R. 6711 Youth act of 1980
      - H.R. 7745 Black lung benefits
      - H.R. 7859 Cuban/refugee education
    - Hawkins, Humphry
    - Impact aid, oversight hearing, 1979 April 8
    - Industry
    - Johnson, Clifford M.
    - Labor
    - Legislative updates
    - Letter inside
    - Lists of bills cosponsored by WRR
    - Materials received on H.R. 9514, 4476, 4326
    - Metrification
    - Migrant farm workers
    - Military
    - Municipal revenue bonds
    - National relations act
    - Native American land claims
    - 1980 census
    - Product liability
    - Product neeeds (Box 76)
    - Ratchford, William
    - Ratchford's postal patron `giveaways'
    - Recommendations
    - Schweiker testimony, 1982 budget cuts hearings, 3/31/81
    - Sodium vapor lights
    - State commissions on teacher excellence
    - Tax cut bills
    - Tax reform for non-profit organizations
    - Trucking industry regulation
    - Whip issue paper for end of 96th congress
    - Whip summary 95th congress
    - Whip summary 96th congress
    - Youth employment program
    - Youth extension CSA reauthorization and the older Americans act reauthorization
    - Subcommittee on postsecondary education, (4 folders)
    - Subcommittee on postsecondary education (Box 77-79)
  - House Administration Committee, 1979 - 1980 (Box 80)
    - Capitol hill tourism
    - Clerk hire, (2 folders)
    - Conference board
    - Connecticut credit union
    - Contested elections, (2 folders)
    - Congressman Goodling, Mrs. Eisenhower
    - Election bills, 1980 Fall
    - Electronic voting system
    - Equipment management proposal
    - Federal election commission, (9 folders)
    - Full committee hearing, 1979 April 25, 1980 July 31; (2 folders)
    - Funding resolutions, floor action
    - Grandfather clause, (2 folders)
    - House administration meeting, 1980 September 25
    - Legislative service organization, (2 folders)
    - Legislative service organization, (7 folders) (Box 81)
    - Information policy, 95th congress
    - Libraries and memorials
    - Members, requests for relief
    - Museum services, 1985